<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>snarski</title><link>https://snarski.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on snarski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 08:50:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://snarski.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beating the Cramér-Rao lower bound in free energy calculations</title><link>https://snarski.github.io/posts/beating_the_mle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 08:50:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://snarski.github.io/posts/beating_the_mle/</guid><description>The Cramér-Rao bound is a result in statistics that puts a lower bound on the variance of an unbiased estimator. When an unbiased estimator achieves this lower bound, there is usually not much one can do to &amp;ldquo;improve&amp;rdquo; the estimator. Broadly speaking, maximum likelihood estimators (MLEs) achieve this lower bound1, and the MLE in free energy calculations is sometimes called Multi-State Bennett Acceptance Ratio (MBAR)2345. It is widely accepted that the ideal setting to obtain the lowest possible variance estimate of a free energy difference is to obtain independent samples from a target mixture distribution and use MBAR to process the data.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://snarski.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://snarski.github.io/about/</guid><description>email: masnarski@gmail.com I am a research scientist at D. E. Shaw Research working on algorithm design for free energy calculations and enhanced sampling techniques. My background is in probability theory. I got my Ph.D. at Brown University, in the Division of Applied Mathematics.
I am looking for jobs starting in January 2023. I work in the U.S. on an H-1B visa, and I am interested in obtaining green card status. I am also willing to relocate outside the U.</description></item><item><title>Bounties</title><link>https://snarski.github.io/bounties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://snarski.github.io/bounties/</guid><description>These bounties are meant to inspire others to think about some problems that are of personal interest to me, but they are mostly for fun and probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the only reason to attack a problem. The problems are vaguely stated; please get in touch with me to discuss the problem before you attack it if you have any interest in claiming the bounty.
Bounty #1 (open, $1000 USD, or a goose) Identify the relationship between large deviations Hamiltonian for chemical reaction networks in terms of the potential on an associated Kähler manifold</description></item><item><title>Papers</title><link>https://snarski.github.io/papers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://snarski.github.io/papers/</guid><description>Selected papers
(2021) Times Square sampling: an adaptive algorithm for free energy estimation (Cristian Predescu, Michael Snarski, Avi Robinson-Mosher, Duluxan Sritharan, Tamas Szalay, David E. Shaw) https://arxiv.org/abs/2112.05109
(2021) Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman equations for Chemical Reaction Networks (Michael Snarski) https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.00514
Other papers
(2020) Splitting algorithms for rare event simulation over long time intervals (Paul Dupuis, Michael Snarski, Anne Buijsrogge) Annals of Applied Probability, Vol. 3 (no 6), pp.</description></item></channel></rss>